[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So, in a bar chart for example, we can use glyphs to represent more than just
例如在柱状图中 我们可以用图元表示
the actual value of data elements, we can use glyphs to represent their variants.
数据元素实际值以外的东西 用图元表示它们的变化
So in this case if we have bars, we can put a glyph at the top of each bar
这里我们已经有了柱形 可以在每个柱形顶端放上
indicating the value, but we can also add information, for
一个表示数值的图元 但也可以增加其他信息
example, standard deviation or variants.
比如标准差或者变化
And, in fact, where the mean or median value is indicated and
事实上 也可以用来表示平均数 或者中位数
where the data varies, so these could be 25%, 75% bars.
或者数据的范围 这里可以是25%-75%的比例
And we can see in some cases that the distribution of data that gets
可以看到 一些情况下 某些区段的数据聚集到一起
aggregated and represented as a single bar,
被表示为一个单独的柱形
the actual distribution is skewed in one direction or another.
但实际的分布倾斜于某一方向
In tables, you can use glyphs, you can represent entries as, for
在表格中 你可以用图元 表示表格元素
example, colors, and that's a kind of a glyph, a very simple glyph.
例如颜色 这是个图元 一个非常简单的图元
But mapping table values to color is a very common thing, and
把表格的值映射到 颜色上非常常见
we're all used to this and seeing weather maps where heat is mapped to color,
我们很习惯这一点 比如这个案例中
as for example, this example here.
这里的气象图就把 温度映射到颜色上
Quantitatively mapping color is not necessarily
量化地把颜色和值对应起来
the most effective way for perceptual accuracy.
不一定是视觉上 最为精确的表达手法
We can tell that it's colder up here and warmer down here,
可以看出这里比较冷 这里比较热
we just might not be able to tell how much colder or how much warmer it is unless
我们没办法说出到底冷了多少 或者热了多少 除非
we go to the reference here, and try to make an equivalence on this
去看图例 然后把图例和图案对应
legend here showing what the average temperature is for this particular month.
这里的备注显示出 当月平均气温
And you can do this discretely as well.
你也可以把它离散化
This is an example of continuous variables.
这里是一个连续变量的例子
You can do this discretely, and we do this in computer science all the time.
你可以把它离散化 在计算机科学里常这么做
If I have a program that I'm trying to optimize, I might change one parameter
如果我有程序需要优化 我会离散地改变参数的值
some discrete number of times, and some other parameter some
这个改几次 那个改几次
discrete number of times, and try to find the sweet spot in terms of performance.
试图找到一个 使性能最佳的组合
The lowest performance here I'm displaying in red,
这里我把性能最低的点 表示为红色
233 is the optimal value here,
233是最优的值
and I can see which parameter of values are giving me worse results.
可以看到哪个参数组合 会给出不太好的结果
And these things may jump around quite a bit.
这些数据可能有变来变去
Programs tend to behave non-linearly as you change these parameters
程序往往会 随着参数而非线性变化
because the systems they run on are quite complicated.
因为运行的系统很复杂
But having these glyphs, basically these numbers represented as color as well,
但有了这些图元 通过用这些颜色来表达数据
helps you hone in on the good values.
就可以突显好的数据
And this one was enabled just using Microsoft Excel.
这个是用微软Excel实现的
The conditional formatting option allows you to
条件格式可以让你
represent values with color as well.
用颜色来表示值
So you can also use glyphs to do high dimensional visualization.
你也可以用图元来 做高维数据的可视化
So in this case this is worlds within worlds,
本例中 这是个世界中的小世界
I've set up horizontal and vertical nominal,
我设定好了水平 和竖直轴的类别量
categorical axes and when I'm plotting inside
每个格子里
each of these table cells, is a separate plot, it's a scatter plot.
又有个单独的图形 这里是个散点图
I just happen to have one data point in the scatter plot, so
但碰巧这里的散点图 都只有一个数据点
I've embedded a two dimensional plot in each element of a two dimensional table.
所以我在每个二维的表格元中 都嵌入了一个二维的图形
So that enables you to look at four dimensional data
这样你就可以看到 四维的数据了
as basically a two dimensional table of two-dimensional plots.
因为这是个二维的表格 里面有二维的数据
In this case what I'm doing is I've got a two-dimensional table of glyphs.
在这里 我所做的是 建一个由图元组成的二维表格
Each glyph happens to be a two-dimensional plot.
每个图元恰是一个二维图形
And so I'm looking in this case at life expectancy, and
这里 我看的是 每一年的预期寿命
I'm looking at the rates of infant mortality inside each year from 2000,
现在看的是婴儿每年的死亡率 从2000 2001
2001, 2002, 2003, 2004.
还有2002 2003 2004
And then vertically I'm looking at the various continents or regions, and
在竖直方向上 看到的是 不同的大陆或者地区
I'm looking at the life expectancy measured inside each one of those.
这里看到的是每个区域内的预期寿命
So I've got an outer table that's looking at the year and
这样我就得到了 一个大表格 横轴是年份
vertically looking at the region of the world, and
纵轴是地区
then inside each year and each region of the world,
在每个年份-地区里
I'm plotting infant mortality versus life expectancy.
这里描绘了婴儿死亡率 和预期寿命的对比
You can see some shifts in the data as we move across different areas of the world.
可以看到 在世界不同地区 数据也有变化
And you can see some shifts in infant mortality, but
这里有地区间 婴儿存活率的变化
you can see that there aren't as many shifts as you move from year to year.
但随着年份推进 地区内部的 变化不是很大
There's another interesting glyph that you can use called Chernoff faces, and
这里还有个有趣的图元 叫做 Chernoff 脸图
in this case you're creating a table, some other layout, but
这里建了一个表格 或一些其他的结构
the data points are being plotted with faces, and the attributes of the face
但每个数据点以脸的方式表示
are indicating various measures of some dimension of the data set.
脸的样子显示出 数据集在一些维度上的表示
In this case this is 12 state judges as
本例显示了律师们对 12个州法官的评分
rated by lawyers and you can map certain features, certain aspects,
法官们在某些特点 某些方面被打分
of the way the state judges were being measured, for example, the number of
比如他们的论断被推翻的次数 会被映射到表情上
times they were overturned, might change the expression from happy to sad.
使他们显得开心或者不开心
And the size of the face may be the number of cases they've seen.
脸的大小则表示了 他们经历的案件数
So, you know, this face may look quite large, and this face look
你看 这个脸看起来很大 这个脸很小
quite small because this state judge has reviewed more cases than has this judge.
因为相比后者而言 前者看的案件更多
And so you can't make value judgments based on the appearance of the faces, but
虽然不能以相貌判断人
the appearance of the faces and the expressions that they
但此图中的面相和表情
have can give you another data channel that you can perceive and remember,
却可以给你另一个渠道 帮助你感知和记忆数据
actually quite well as a way of finding interesting aspects of the data,
这也是一种表达数据 的有趣方式
things in the data that stand out.
尤其表达了数据中 值得关注的方面
So we learned that we can use glyphs to display many other attributes
我们学到了 在用柱形图等图表 进行可视化时
of our data when we're using a chart or some other data visualization.
还可以用图元 表示数据中其他方面的属性
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community